Jerry Fitzner

High Point, NC | 307-299-5611 | <u>ifitzner1@gmail.com</u> <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Github</u> | <u>Blog</u> | <u>Portfolio</u>

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full Stack Software engineer experienced in Ruby on Rails, React, and JavaScript based programming. With a background in technical problem-solving, I collaborate well on a team, communicate clearly, and remain calm in chaotic situations. I learn from failure, thrive on feedback, and am self-driven. My love of software development stems from the challenges it brings to create accessible and easy to use software for all.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, Ruby, HTML, CSS, React JS, Redux, Ruby on Rails, SQL, SQLite3, OOP, Rails API, GIT, PostgreSQL

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Incident Command App - Github | Demo

An app that allows an emergency commander to keep track of emergency incidents, and resources allocated.

- Implemented encrypted password storage through the 'bcrypt' gem in rails.
- Maintained state utilizing Redux.
- Developed a full stack application utilizing REACT on the front end and Rails on the backend.
- Utilized Rails to create a functioning API with custom and RESTful routes.

Student Fundraising App - Github Frontend | Github Backend | Demo

An app that allows a youth leader/teacher to keep track of the fundraising efforts of their students and donors.

- Utilized REACT with Sinatra to build a full stack web-based application.
- Created custom routes to implement full C.R.U.D. on the backend.
- Implemented state to maintain various functionality of the application.

EXPERIENCE

Photobiz, LLC, Greensboro, NC

07/2022 - Present

Quality Assurance Specialist

10/2022 - Present

- Plan and execute manual software test plans to ensure quality software is released.
- Ensure software is of quality and meets design specifications for a consistent product.
- Verify issues (bugs) in the software and communicate these issues to the software developers.

Web Consultant 07/2022 - 10/2022

- Assisted customers with utilizing a drag and drop web builder for their websites.
- Created CSS and HTML to assist in the design of customer's websites.

Campbell County Government, Gillette, WY

07/2020 - 09/2021

Deputy Sheriff

- Wrote detailed reports and warrants ensuring accuracy and punctuality.
- Prioritized and responded to emergencies to ensure my work time was used wisely.

Campbell County Government, Gillette, WY

02/2020 - 07/2020

Deputy Emergency Management Coordinator

- Coordinated meetings which allowed various teams to work together to solve large problems.
- Organized multiple agencies and teams by communicating detailed plans to ensure cohesiveness.

City of Gillette, Gillette, WY

04/2014 - 02/2020

Police Officer

- Trained and supervised new officers as a field training officer.
- Directed community impact groups while being awarded Officer of the Year and the Community Involvement Award.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School, Online Program

12/2021 - 02/2023

Software Engineering - Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails, React, and JavaScript program

Gillette Community College, Gillette, WY

09/2011 - 05/2015